<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>J. Brian Shumate</title>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:8080/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>http://localhost:8080</link>
    <description>Personal journal of art &amp; nerdery</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Playing with Fire</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/playing-with-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/playing-with-fire/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For CHARGAUX&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Chill
    is how calmly grooving
    contentment on all faces
    around the square can
    best be described in words

Fire
    shaped like two young and
    beautiful black women who
    delicately and expertly
    shred notes immortal out
    of strings in their hands
Four
    wondrous human souls who
    lit this fire then tend to
    the heart-churning burning
    with casual determination
    and grace of immersion
Fire
    gently burns the center of
    space and casts auditory
    warmth to all who will
    receive its flickering flow
Vibe
    swaddles my heart like
    a mother&amp;#39;s warm arms and
    kisses my face with glowing
    soothing sunshine sounds
Peace
    ringing strings and earthen
    rumbling drums sound out
    a rhythm of tranquility—
    joy delivered through music
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>voxel.js</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/voxel-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28  Aug 2013 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/voxel-js/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last several months, I’ve been playing around with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://voxeljs.com/&quot;&gt;voxel.js&lt;/a&gt;. It’s been great fun with my kids, and useful
for helping to teach my daughter programming with JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/voxel-js/voxeljs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Voxel.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both kids love it for its similarities to Minecraft, and I appreciate
its open source nature and the ability to do things in the browser by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t yet checked out voxel.js, I highly encourage you to do so; it
was built and is maintained by some really cool people, and is a ton of fun
to play with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was built with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://nodejs.org/&quot;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt; JavaScript
platform, is heavily reliant on &lt;a href=&quot;http://threejs.org/&quot;&gt;three.js&lt;/a&gt;, and is
relatively simple to get up and running on your own computer or on a server
near you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving around in the voxel.js world relies on web browser support for mouse
lock (also called &lt;em&gt;pointer lock&lt;/em&gt;) which is supported in contemporary versions
of Chrome and Firefox at least. I have not personally it tried with other web
browsers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are numerous modules which can be used to extend the basic functionality
supplied with voxel.js so that you can introduce characters (&lt;em&gt;critters&lt;/em&gt;),
change physics, play audio, interact with objects, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s even a Voxel Critter Creator, which you can use to design different
critters for use with voxel.js, and it is pretty simple to import existing
Minecraft skins as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/voxel-js/voxel_critter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A voxel critter&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;A neat little red couch voxel “critter”, ready to be used in
  a voxel world or NoSQL database use case near you ;)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, voxel.js is probably one of the coolest JavaScript and game
focused projects going for introducing novice programmers to more advanced
concepts while having a fun time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check it out and don’t forget to marvel at the sheer magnificence that is
Max Ogden’s beard!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vegan Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/vegan-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/vegan-life/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was made aware of a fun website called &lt;a href=&quot;http://thugkitchen.com/&quot;&gt;Thug Kitchen&lt;/a&gt; full of great recipes and knowledge aimed
at helping one “Eat like you give a fuck”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/vegan-life/vegan_life.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Stay stacking dat produce, playa!&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/caseyrosenthal&quot;&gt;fine fellow&lt;/a&gt; who shared the link on Twitter often advocates a vegan
diet, which I think is pretty cool (&lt;em&gt;working on it&lt;/em&gt;), I made the quick little
tattoo style thing you see above as a thank you to him for his inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surviving San Francisco</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/surviving-san-francisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/surviving-san-francisco/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just got back from San Francisco. It was great to see and meet some of the
folks I’d not seen in a long time or even met yet, and for that I am thankful
to have been to the conference I attended there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/surviving-san-francisco/three_wise_mushrooms.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pipe caps painted to look like mushrooms&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Three Wise Mushrooms&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might or might not have also learned a great deal there too, but the jury
is still out on that. (&lt;em&gt;insert nervous laughter here&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surviving the trip and returning to &lt;em&gt;the south&lt;/em&gt; is also a rewarding
feeling as I am developing a severe dislike of the American travel by airline
experience as I age, and am prone to shutting down during the worst of times
while enduring said travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that out of the way, this post is about art and photographs. I took
far fewer photographs with my trusty smart phone this time around than ever,
which is both liberating from the perspective of just being in the moment,
but also kind of a bummer in hindsight now that I look over what I was
actually able to capture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here then are a few different shots that I think represent my mindset in
taking in the particularly nasty, brutish, and short experience of that
area known as &lt;em&gt;Union Square&lt;/em&gt;. While there is filth everywhere in sight,
sound, and smell, there is a also a &lt;em&gt;beauty of the struggle&lt;/em&gt; and in the simple
artistic expression hidden all around the area as typified by the first
photograph above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/surviving-san-francisco/stay_warm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;homeless person under blanket&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Stay Warm&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amidst the everyday consumption and tunnel visioned quests for greater
prosperity going on in the city are of course, the numerous homeless people.
They’re essentially lamp posts, hydrants, or excrement to most area “natives”
and are to be stepped around or over as such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They’re to be tuned out like so many advertisements and graffiti. Never mind
that they too are human beings; they are &lt;em&gt;different human beings&lt;/em&gt;, a
sub-species unlike the rest of us upwardly mobile and privileged who fight
to keep our shit together within the system so that we might have loved ones
and a place to come home to at the end of each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The streets are cold and unforgiving, so a good drunken stupor and warm
blanket are the coping mechanism needed by most at the end of the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do not share the above cold and inhumane view of these persons, and
on the contrary have even half a conscience, you can’t help but know a taste
of Siddartha’s painful conflicted state by gazing upon those less fortunate in
their most vulnerable condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/surviving-san-francisco/castro_trolley.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The F line&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;The F Line&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a more typical capture one expects to see from San Francisco; the
famous F Line trolley that runs from The Embarcadero all the way to The
Castro. Everyone who’s studied or been to San Francisco knows these iconic and
charmingly antiquated modes of transportation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They’re simultaneously bold and comforting in that they stand out from all
the surrounding modernity while providing a perpetual shout out to how it
used to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The early morning light present when I spotted her slowly creaking by on
Market Street was nothing short of spectacular and this photograph barely
even begins to convey what I saw that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/surviving-san-francisco/stacks.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A distant building and some sort of stack&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Silent Stacks&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city’s collection of weight never fails to impress upon me; be it
skyscrapers or smokestacks. One can be doing the most mundane of things, such
as fetching a morning coffee and in turning around to face another direction,
the city will reveal her various juxtaposed collections of mass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sheer size and weight counterpoised against our small selves and little lives
is both disturbing and exciting. We built this spectacular city and in turn,
the city builds into us an awe at every moment where the unexpected looms
over any scene it seems to not belong in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s the name of the game here, a paradox of plenty and of nothing &amp;mdash; a balance of extremes that is constantly in motion and always on the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/surviving-san-francisco/yellow.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;homeless shoeless man wearing yellow&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Yellow was Van Gogh’s Favorite Color&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A homeless man stands out like an anti-ghost of the streets; not panhandling,
not scrounging the sidewalk for cigarette butts, and not really interacting
with anyone in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He exists there in bold and blazing yellow, like a confused captain whose
ship has recently run aground, appraising the situation of a new day and contemplating his survival. Or is he merely pondering on where he can
score a new pair of shoes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing his bare feet, I could not help but be reminded that there was a pair
of shoes lying on the sidewalk presumably without an owner just blocks away…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alpacawhal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/alpacawhal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/alpacawhal/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A mythical beast of supremely pointy compassion…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/alpacawhal/alpacawhal.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-mighty-alpacawhal&quot;&gt;The Mighty Alpacawhal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted my own hybrid mythical creature because unicorns and gummy bears can
only take the imagination so far. I pondered on this for a few days and came
to the conclusion that combining a couple actual creatures from land and sea
would have the effect I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alpacawhal is the result of my pondering and subsequent rendering and I
couldn’t be more pleased with it. In my imagination, Alpacawhal is a kind
and compassionate creature, and it can often be aloof or even goofy, but if
you fuck with it, it will throw down, lower its head, and gore your ass away.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Capacitor Cowgirl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/capacitor-cowgirl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/capacitor-cowgirl/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is not official Banksy anything.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/capacitor-cowgirl/bankruptsy_capacitor_cowgirl.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Capacitor Cowgirl&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just a mashup of original Banksy imagery with my own ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m simply using the Banksy imagery for personal reasons, reasons which I
will henceforth refer to as &lt;em&gt;Bankruptsy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With some degree of seriouness, I am free to use this imagery per the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.banksy.co.uk/shop/shop21.html&quot;&gt;Banksy website shop&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re welcome to download whatever you wish from this site for personal
use. However, making your own art or merchandise and passing it off as
‘official’ or authentic Banksy artwork is bad and very wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of Mang</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/evolution-of-mang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/evolution-of-mang/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is where mang has arrived; stooped over and walking into hazards
while actively communicating via technologies to people in ways they might
not necessarily even do face-to-face on a daily basis any longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/evolution-of-mang/evolution_of_mang.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fear not however, as the worlds largest advertising company is racing to
save the day with a set of glasses which will complete the evolution of
mang into a costly biological sensor network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that’s progress!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Head Swap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/head-swap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/head-swap/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is not official Banksy anything.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/head-swap/bankruptsy_head_swap.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just a mashup of original Banksy imagery with my own ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m simply using the Banksy imagery for personal reasons, reasons which I
will henceforth refer to as &lt;em&gt;Bankruptsy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With some degree of seriouness, I am free to use this imagery per the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.banksy.co.uk/shop/shop21.html&quot;&gt;Banksy website shop&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re welcome to download whatever you wish from this site for personal
use. However, making your own art or merchandise and passing it off as
‘official’ or authentic Banksy artwork is bad and very wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Riak on FreeBSD ZFS Jails</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/riak-freebsd-jails-zfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/riak-freebsd-jails-zfs/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a ramshackle and slipshod introduction to establishing a specific
flavor of FreeBSD environment under which to &lt;em&gt;evaluate&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;test&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;play&lt;/em&gt;
with &lt;a href=&quot;http://basho.com/products/riak-overview/&quot;&gt;Riak&lt;/a&gt;, the fantastic
distributed database by Basho Technologies, Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PLEASE NOTE: This content contains outdated and possibly irrelevant information.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration and processes described in this guide &lt;strong&gt;should not&lt;/strong&gt;
be construed as advice for use in production environments. Providing
such information is beyond the scope of this guide as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals-for-this-guide&quot;&gt;Goals For This Guide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s get a clear understanding of what I’m going to be describing to you in
this guide out of the way before we roll up our sleeves and commence to hasty
typing, bug smashing, and eventual triumphant success with accompanying
celebratory beverages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point of this guide is do something closely resembling the following on
my modest bare metal quad-core machine with only 16GB RAM, and approximately 200GB of SAS 10k rotational storage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install FreeBSD (I am using 8.3 for my example system) on suitable hardware for running a small &lt;strong&gt;test&lt;/strong&gt; Riak cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure the system to function as a jail environment host and allocate some of the available storage for a ZFS zpool for jail environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use ezjail with ZFS specific functionality to create a base jail environment plus a flavor of jail which will comprise each Riak node&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creation and minimal configuration of each Riak node&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launch nodes, join nodes, and test our cluster in various ways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss minimal system tuning for best use in certain scenarios&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss tools for operational and performance testing and monitoring of the cluster (ex: Basho Bench, Riaknostic, Riemann)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-host-machine&quot;&gt;The Host Machine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following notes pertain to work done on the physical server for establishing a jails environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;savor-the-riak-jail-flavor&quot;&gt;Savor The Riak Jail Flavor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will first build and lightly configure a Riak jail flavor, so that
spinning up subsequent Riak nodes will take much less time. The goal here is
to build a Riak node, and do initial common software package installation,
but without any unique configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;riak-dependencies-supporting-software&quot;&gt;Riak, Dependencies &amp;amp; Supporting Software&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Riak 1.1.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erlang R14B04&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Git&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sudo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the jail is booted, we can install Riak dependencies and supporting software. As of this writing and with FreeBSD 8.3-RELEASE, the ports tree offers Erlang R14B04, which is compatible with the Riak version 1.1.2 we’ll be using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use your preferred options/discretion for particular builds of the software ports listed below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;lang-bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;built_in&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; /usr/ports/lang/erlang &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make install distclean
&lt;span class=&quot;built_in&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; /usr/ports/ftp/curl &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make install distclean
&lt;span class=&quot;built_in&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; /usr/ports/devel/git &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make install distclean
&lt;span class=&quot;built_in&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; /usr/ports/sysutils/screen &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make install distclean
&lt;span class=&quot;built_in&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; /usr/ports/security/&lt;span class=&quot;built_in&quot;&gt;sudo&lt;/span&gt; &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make install distclean
&lt;span class=&quot;built_in&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; /usr/ports/editors/vim-lite &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make install distclean
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can install package versions of the above like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;lang-bash&quot;&gt;pkg_add -r curl erlang git screen &lt;span class=&quot;built_in&quot;&gt;sudo&lt;/span&gt; vim-lite
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;notes-for-building-riak-on-freebsd-8-3-release&quot;&gt;Notes for Building Riak on FreeBSD 8.3-RELEASE&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The BSD make(1) dance&lt;/em&gt;: BSD has its own build toolchain in addition to some
GNU build tools, such as &lt;code&gt;gmake&lt;/code&gt;. This  can pose an issue when building Riak,
so we can perform a small, rather inelegant, but temporary workaround:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From within the jail host:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;lang-bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;built_in&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; /usr/local/jails/basejail/usr/bin
mv make bsd-make
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From within the jail being used to build the Riak flavor:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;lang-bash&quot;&gt;ln -sf /usr/local/bin/gmake /usr/local/bin/make
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we can download the Riak 1.1.2 source, and compile a &lt;code&gt;rel&lt;/code&gt; release on the initial node:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;lang-bash&quot;&gt;curl -O downloads.basho.com.s3-website-us-east-&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;.amazonaws.com/riak/&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1.1&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1.1&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;/riak-&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1.1&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;.tar.gz
tar zxf riak-&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1.1&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;.tar.gz
&lt;span class=&quot;built_in&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; riak-&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1.1&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
gmake rel
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provided the build was successful, you now have a complete Riak node
contained in &lt;code&gt;rel/riak&lt;/code&gt;. Check out the official Basho documentation on
&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.basho.com/riak/latest/cookbooks/Basic-Cluster-Setup/&quot;&gt;Basic Cluster Setup&lt;/a&gt; to learn about configuring a Riak cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: Don’t forget to undo the hackity &lt;code&gt;gmake&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt; jigglings so that
you’ll be able to build ports, etc. later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wash hands, dry on pants and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, one can also use &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; to pull in custom environment
settings, dotfiles, etc. to ease operation and administration of the nodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;system-tuning-notes&quot;&gt;System Tuning Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some minimal system tuning notes. If you want more detailed
information, see Basho’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.basho.com/riak/latest/cookbooks/Linux-Performance-Tuning/&quot;&gt;system tuning documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;open-files-limit&quot;&gt;Open Files Limit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riak opens many files during operation; ensure that the open files limit is
set to an adequate level for operation. The default minimum value is &lt;code&gt;4906&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mounting-with-noatime&quot;&gt;Mounting With noatime&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure that you use the &lt;code&gt;noatime&lt;/code&gt; option for mounting any volumes
which will store Riak data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;clustering-notes&quot;&gt;Clustering Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After bootstrapping each node, you’ll need to assemble them into a cluster.
In this example, I’ve got five nodes using a resolvable fully qualified
domain name scheme like this: &lt;code&gt;riak1.example.com&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;riak2.example.com&lt;/code&gt;, …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great start to understanding building a basic cluster is the Basho
documentation &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.basho.com/riak/latest/cookbooks/Basic-Cluster-Setup/&quot;&gt;Basic Cluster Setup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simplest process for joining the nodes to form a cluster is to issue the
&lt;code&gt;riak-admin join&lt;/code&gt; command from N-1 nodes instructing them to join the first
node, like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;lang-bash&quot;&gt;ssh riak2.example.com riak-admin join riak@riak1.example.com
Success: sent join request to &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;'riak@riak1.example.com'&lt;/span&gt;
ssh riak3.example.com riak-admin join riak@riak1.example.com
Success: sent join request to &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;'riak@riak1.example.com'&lt;/span&gt;
ssh riak4.example.com riak-admin join riak@riak1.example.com
Success: sent join request to &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;'riak@riak1.example.com'&lt;/span&gt;
ssh riak5.example.com riak-admin join riak@riak1.example.com
Success: sent join request to &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;'riak@riak1.example.com'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As shown in the above example, you should expect to see a success message for
each node’s join attempt. If there are problems, you could see an error
message instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;riak-admin-ringready&quot;&gt;riak-admin ringready&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a bit of time and provided you saw success messages for each join
request, you can verify that the cluster is ready with a command like this
executed from any of the nodes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;lang-bash&quot;&gt;ssh riak1.example.com riak-admin ringready
Attempting to restart script through &lt;span class=&quot;built_in&quot;&gt;sudo&lt;/span&gt; -H -u riak
TRUE All nodes agree on the ring [&lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;'riak@riak1.example.com'&lt;/span&gt;,
                                  &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;'riak@riak2.example.com'&lt;/span&gt;,
                                  &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;'riak@riak3.example.com'&lt;/span&gt;,
                                  &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;'riak@riak4.example.com'&lt;/span&gt;,
                                  &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;'riak@riak5.example.com'&lt;/span&gt;]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some other initial checks of the cluster you can try are &lt;code&gt;riak-admin test&lt;/code&gt;
and gathering status through &lt;code&gt;riak-admin status&lt;/code&gt; and the HTTP interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;riak-admin-test&quot;&gt;riak-admin test&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;lang-bash&quot;&gt;ssh riak1.example.com riak-admin test
Attempting to restart script through &lt;span class=&quot;built_in&quot;&gt;sudo&lt;/span&gt; -H -u riak
Successfully completed &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;built_in&quot;&gt;read&lt;/span&gt;/write cycle to &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;'riak@riak1.example.com'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;riak-admin-status&quot;&gt;riak-admin status&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;http-stats&quot;&gt;HTTP stats&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use curl to get stats from the HTTP interface like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;lang-bash&quot;&gt;curl loadbalancer.example.com/stats
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can run &lt;code&gt;curl&lt;/code&gt; directly against your load balancer IP as in the
example above or against something like &lt;code&gt;localhost:8098&lt;/code&gt; when on
the node directly, but you &lt;strong&gt;should not expose Riak directly to any public
interfaces&lt;/strong&gt;. Always run Riak behind some kind of load balancer or reverse
proxy arrangement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;diagnose-manage-monitor&quot;&gt;Diagnose, Manage &amp;amp; Monitor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;diagnosing-issues&quot;&gt;Diagnosing Issues&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One great utility for performing initial diagnosis of troubles with your
Riak cluster is &lt;a href=&quot;http://riaknostic.basho.com&quot;&gt;Riaknostic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riaknostic ties into the &lt;code&gt;riak-admin&lt;/code&gt; command, providing a &lt;code&gt;diag&lt;/code&gt; subcommand
that can be run alone for a wealth of diagnostic or with options for specific
checks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;managing-your-cluster&quot;&gt;Managing Your Cluster&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riak is an operations friendly database and the included command line tools
provide an excellent management interface. You are strongly encouraged to
familiarize yourself with the &lt;code&gt;riak&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;riak-admin&lt;/code&gt; commands if you will
be interacting with Riak often via the command line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional tools are available for managing Riak with a more user friendly,
contemporary web user interface. The most popular of such tools is Basho’s own
&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.basho.com/riak/latest/references/appendices/Riak-Control/&quot;&gt;Riak Control&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;riak-control&quot;&gt;Riak Control&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riak Control ships with Riak and can be enabled quite easily to provide a
more visually oriented interface to Riak’s inner workings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riak Control provides the following functionality out of the box:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More functionality is in the works. Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.basho.com/riak/latest/references/appendices/Riak-Control/&quot;&gt;official documentation for Riak Control&lt;/a&gt; to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;performance-testing&quot;&gt;Performance Testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A popular tool for performance testing, bulk loading keys, and other testing
odds and ends is &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:8080/articles/riak-freebsd-jails-zfs/(http://docs.basho.com/riak/latest/cookbooks/Benchmarking/&quot;&gt;Basho Bench&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basho Bench can performance test various aspects of a system like Riak and
then generate nice R based graphs as a final output option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://freebsd.org&quot;&gt;FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freebsd.org/doc/handbook/jails.html&quot;&gt;FreeBSD Jails&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.basho.com/riak/latest/&quot;&gt;Riak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.basho.com/riak/latest/cookbooks/Basic-Cluster-Setup/&quot;&gt;Basic Cluster Setup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.basho.com/riak/latest/cookbooks/Linux-Performance-Tuning/&quot;&gt;Linux Performance Tuning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://riaknostic.basho.com&quot;&gt;Riaknostic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/basho/riaknostic&quot;&gt;Riaknostic Github project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.basho.com/riak/latest/references/appendices/Riak-Control/&quot;&gt;Riak Control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/basho/riak_control&quot;&gt;Riak Control Github project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.basho.com/riak/latest/cookbooks/Benchmarking/&quot;&gt;Benchmarking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Questlonger</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/questlonger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/questlonger/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My humble attempt at punctuation invention&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/questlonger/questlonger.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Questlonger&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I invented what I think is an exciting new form of punctuation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allow me to introduce the &lt;em&gt;Questlonger&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What exactly &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a Questlonger? It’s a simple bit of punctuation that
combines all of the unfinished tension of an ellipsis with the
curiosity a question mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intent is to demonstrate an unfinished question or question which will
not readily be answerable in the text immediately surrounding a Questlonger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, were it not for the wonderful television show
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Futurama&quot;&gt;Futurama&lt;/a&gt;, I could not have so
easily arrived at the name for such an odd thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For that, I am very grateful to the awesome Professor Farnsworth and his
wonderful invention, the &lt;em&gt;Fing-Longer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maps with Public Data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/maps-public-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 09:28:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/maps-public-data/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve been having a great time working with public data and maps.
The main reason that it has been so much fun revolves around the
specific technology stack I am using to design and present them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/maps-public-data/Zodiac_research.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE: This information is out of date and the embedded maps which used
to exist here are now static screenshots.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above screenshot shows one example of a San Francisco Bay Area map that
I’ve been gradually working on as part of some map related research into
providing a geographical context into a specific set of past events which
occurred in that area (sorry for the vagueness).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been able to quickly create and present some visually interesting
maps which convey useful data on a range of subjects using technologies
from &lt;a href=&quot;http://mapbox.com&quot; title=&quot;MapBox&quot;&gt;MapBox&lt;/a&gt; such as
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mapbox.com/#/tilemill&quot; title=&quot;TileMill&quot;&gt;TileMill&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mapbox.com/#/tilestream&quot; title=&quot;TileStream&quot;&gt;TileStream&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mapbox.github.com/wax/&quot; title=&quot;Wax&quot;&gt;Wax&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a brief overview of the MapBox solution, and some of the maps I
have recently created with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;think-globally-map-locally&quot;&gt;Think globally, map locally&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you’ll see, the following maps all center around my local area, and since
I’m mostly experimenting with the technology right now, these maps are on
random subjects, though I do strive to ensure they are accurate. Please
tweet &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/brianshumate&quot;&gt;@brianshumate&lt;/a&gt; if
you find any serious flaw, and I’ll do my best to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;longboarding-spots-in-boone-north-carolina&quot;&gt;Longboarding spots in Boone, North Carolina&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/maps-public-data/Boone_longboarding_spots.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d previously made some nice maps with longboarding
spots I frequent in Boone, NC based on
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openstreetmap.org/&quot; title=&quot;OpenStreetMap&quot;&gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt;, so I
thought I’d do something like that with the MapBox tools first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth noting that what you see in the above map is not just a
service that I am pointing to and dropping markers on. This map was
designed using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.census.gov/geo/www/tiger/tgrshp2009/tgrshp2009.html&quot; title=&quot;2009 TIGER/Line&amp;reg; Shapefiles&quot;&gt;U.S. Census
Bureau&lt;/a&gt;
data combined with my own &lt;a href=&quot;http://geojson.org/&quot; title=&quot;GeoJSON&quot;&gt;GeoJSON&lt;/a&gt; data
and styling rules using TileMill to arrive at the look and feel it has,
including the styling of land areas, roadways, water bodies, marker
data, and legends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The TileMill application is available for OS X or Linux. It has a most excellent and intuitive user interface and will quickly feel familiar to web folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/maps-public-data/TileMill_user_interface.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The TileMill app (&lt;em&gt;shown in screen shot above&lt;/em&gt;) has an excellent browser
based user interface where you use the CSS-like language
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mapbox/carto&quot; title=&quot;carto styling language&quot;&gt;carto&lt;/a&gt; to
define the styles for your map’s layers and data. There’s also a very
handy carto reference built right into TileMill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carto&lt;/strong&gt; is an advanced CSS like language with nesting, variables, and
other cool features similar to CSS meta languages like LESS and SASS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;MBTiles&lt;/strong&gt; specification is an interesting new way to store map
tilesets and their associated metadata in an SQLite database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After designing the map in TileMill, I use its export features to
generate a set of image tiles in a format
(&lt;a href=&quot;http://mbtiles.org/&quot;&gt;MBTiles&lt;/a&gt; that the
TileStream tile server can serve up to any kind of web application or
site imaginable. TileMill can also export your map creations as PNG or
PDF images, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I use the &lt;a href=&quot;http://modestmaps.com/&quot; title=&quot;Modest Maps&quot;&gt;Modest Maps&lt;/a&gt;
and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mapbox/wax&quot; title=&quot;Wax open source web mapping tools&quot;&gt;Wax&lt;/a&gt;
libraries to stream the map tilesets from my TileStream server, and
display them here as embedded interactive maps!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s also putting it quite modestly, indeed; you can do some seriously
amazing things with this trio of technologies, and some solid JavaScript
chops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://developmentseed.org/&quot; title=&quot;Development Seed&quot;&gt;Development Seed home
page&lt;/a&gt; is a perfect
example of the kinds of amazing map visualizations one can create with
these tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;terrain-visualization&quot;&gt;Terrain visualization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/maps-public-data/Boone_shaded_map.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For creating the terrain visualization in the above map screenshot,
I consulted MapBox documentation on using GDAL DEM utilities and STRM image
data: &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.mapbox.com/kb/tilemill/terrain-visualization-with-digital-elevation-models-and-gdal&quot; title=&quot;Terrain visualization with digital elevation models and GDAL&quot;&gt;Terrain visualization with digital elevation models and
GDAL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This simple map is a proof of concept, and uses only one interactive
layer, the names of Watauga county communities, which are displayed on
mouse over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned quickly from making maps like this one, that it is a very
serious craft requiring one work with a blend of design concerns like
color theory along with more nerdy pursuits, such as command line
wrangling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that I am not a Cartographer and I have a lot to learn about map
making, but I’m looking forward to making even better and more visually
interesting maps with these tools in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are all of the Github repositories for the MapBox projects mentined
in this post: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mapbox/carto&quot; title=&quot;Carto&quot;&gt;Carto&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mapbox/tilemill&quot; title=&quot;TileMill&quot;&gt;TileMill&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mapbox/tilestream&quot; title=&quot;TileStream&quot;&gt;TileStream&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mapbox/wax&quot; title=&quot;Wax&quot;&gt;Wax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I previously mentioned, the documentation for all of Mapbox’s tools
is great; it’s well written, and uses good examples. Further, the
projects are all open source and accessible on
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mapbox&quot; title=&quot;MapBox Github&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;watauga-county-food-service-ratings&quot;&gt;Watauga County food service ratings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/maps-public-data/Wautaga_food_service_ratings.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This map combines public health inspection data which is scraped and
converted to GeoJSON for restaurants and other food service services
with the restaurant locations color coded by rating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can hover over each point for the name of the location and the
rating, and you can click to get a bit more information for a given
location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-summary&quot;&gt;In summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data used for these maps comes from the following sources: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.census.gov/geo/www/tiger/tgrshp2009/tgrshp2009.html&quot;&gt;2009
TIGER/Line&amp;reg;
Shapefiles&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://watauga.nc.gegov.com/index.cfm&quot; title=&quot;Watauga County Health Department&quot;&gt;Watauga County Health
Department&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.jpl.nasa.gov/srtm/&quot; title=&quot;Shuttle Radar Topography Mission&quot;&gt;Shuttle Radar Topography
Mission&lt;/a&gt;,
and my phone’s GPS. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MapBox stack is very well made open source software with great
attention to detail, and the folks behind it are responsive, helpful,
and friendly. I’m looking forward to making more awesome maps, and
seeing where this solution goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up next: &lt;strong&gt;fancy maps in mobile apps&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Love and Longboards</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/love-and-longboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2010 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/love-and-longboards/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alternative rock band name + longboarding passion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/love-and-longboards/love-and-longboards.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Love and Longboards&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s my take on a mashup of the band Love and Rockets logo with a longboard
obviously replacing the rocket part of the equation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>